

Lucas Stahl

Libertyville, IL | cell: 224.513.9122 | Stahl1109@gmail.com | www.stahlwalker.org | in linkedin.com/in/lucasstahl | 🔘 github.com/Stahlwalker



MARKETING MANAGER & WEB PROGRAMMER

Motivated professional with fourteen plus years of experience in digital marketing, business development and web programming. Skilled in managing projects from concept to completion, designing educational strategies and coaching individuals to success. Adaptable and transformational leader with an ability to work independently, creating effective presentations, and developing opportunities that further establish organization goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, JSON, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB, Design, Social Media, Mailchimp, Film editing (Adobe Premiere & Final Cut Pro), Adobe InDesign and Photoshop

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HERE Technologies - Chicago, IL

Developer Marketing Manager

(11/2018 - Present)

- Executed scalable campaigns to drive growth in adoption of tools and APIs
- Achieved 27% growth year-over-year in 2019.
- Managed strategic marketing growth initiatives for developers.
- Global campaign management for self-serve and paid plans driving developer growth.
- Implemented developer driven email campaigns and monthly developer newsletters.
- Channel marketing and go-to-market strategies for marketplaces.
- Directed input from key partners into marketing programs and integrated multi-channel campaigns (e.g. events, email, paid search, paid social, display, retargeting and content marketing).

Northwestern Medicine - Chicago, IL

Senior Marketing Specialist

(08/2015 - 11/2018)

- Managed both paid and organic social media tactics with high conversion success.
- Digital marketing lead for entire north region, focused on email marketing, web content/auditing, SEO, and metrics reporting through Google Analytics.
- Managed yearly marketing budgets for service lines, exceeding a quarter million.
- Developed content for new product/service launches and brand campaigns.
- Sponsorships activation and event planning.
- Replaced costly agencies fees, saving thousands of dollars through in-house creative development.
- Digital team manager for over three years during the launch of the new Lake Forest Hospital, resulting in website migration and owning the content on several microsites.

Marketing Specialist (04/2012 - 08/2015)

Odyssey Hospice Care - Arlington Heights, IL

Account Executive (11/2010 - 04/2012)

Vitas Innovative Hospice Care - Chicago, IL

Sales Representative (08/2009 - 11/2010)

Physiotherapy Associates, Inc. - Chicago, IL

Marketing Manager (02/2007 - 08/2009)Patient Services Manager (12/2005 - 02/2007)

EDUCATION

- Northwestern University- Full Stack Web Development Certificate (May 2018)
- Southern New Hampshire University- Master of Arts, Communications: New Media and Marketing (August 2017)
- Illinois State University- Bachelor of Science, Communications and Media Studies (May 2006)